Hi everyone once again welcome to you the best you
take my self Gaurav and through this video of today
we are going to understand about Open V
what is Open V model here how it is used and we
can install it inside our system and what all we can perform through it
today we are going to see all these things in detail here
see first I would like to talk about
Open V name here is Open
Computer Vision means what do you have it is
a library of computer vision which
you can use inside python now
see if we talk about it this library of computer vision is
an open
source library which is used for machine learning
artificial intelligence face recognition
many such things
along with this what does it do
inside you
which is most helpful for you for computer vision whatever
can be done with it is done inside C
you can easily use it inside C++
with it Windows Linux and Mac OS
Android  As it performs very well inside the system, basically the
open library that you have is the
open civil liability computer vision
library through which you get image
processing, video processing, video
related information etc.
and
after that you
perform different operations here and let's talk about what are the operations
here, which tasks are performed through open and so basically let's talk about
classifying objects, that
means your different objects,
if you want to classify them
under different different objects, then also you do it
for edit notification, here you have to
track the object,
where the object is moving from which place, even then when
you do open and then
what tasks can we perform through open and, let's
discuss about them,
so basically you can classify it, that
means object  Within this, we
can classify which object is what and how it is
working. Along with this, we can also
identify the object to know which
object it is. For example, if I show you this mouse,
you can identify it as to
what it is. Here, there is a mouse. Similarly, the
computer can identify it.
You can
perform such tasks, object tracking,
restoring,
feature matching of images and video
motion analysis. So,
all these tasks can be
performed here through OpenCC.
Next, let's talk about
how OpenCC works. So, basically,
what OpenCC does here is that if you have any
image, it takes that image
into greyscale and either it takes it into greyscale
or it goes
into RGB colour. Now,
what does grey colour mean? If we talk about it here,
grey colour means black
and white images. You can compare them here.
So for example, if you see here, if you have
an image, what does it do to that image? It
takes a black and white image and
what does it do inside the black and white image, a pixel which is
a block, it brings that block
and what does it do inside it,
you have small different color boxes, so here it
matches and
what does it do with those matching boxes, it displays them in a matrix format in front of you,
so that whatever thing you want to change inside it
or whatever data you want to collect from it,
you can separate it easily. So
basically, if we talk about open and here
you have grayscale and RGB colors, it
reduces these two wedges. Basically, if we talk about the
image inside it, the
pixels of the image, the
meaning of pixels here is that, like the
video that you are watching now,
inside this video also you have a small
part in which you are seeing the color,
like here if I talk about the face only, then
in the face, if the color is skin color,
here if I take a small color like this  If I
talk about this thing, then what do you have inside it, there are
pixels, what do you have inside those pixels, just
like the colors inside it, similarly
what do you have inside RCB, the thing is visible
and when I remote it here, that is, if I
see the details of Open CB, then
what does it show us here, it
shows a matrix, in that matrix,
inside that color,
inside that particular box, which colors are arranged in which formation,
all that is
visible here, so what all this work is done here is
performed here through Open CC, now let's talk about Open CC,
why are you doing it, do not do any other system,
first of all, if we talk about here, then
what is your Open CC, it is free of
cost, there will be no charges in it, you
can work on it by installing i10 in D directly, let's talk about the second thing
here, it works on C and C plus plus, that is,
its red
library which is written on C,
what is C plus plus, basically, so basically C
O C plus  What is your plus, it
works fast here, so that's why we
use it the most and it consumes very
less RAM. Let's
talk about the second thing here, the open source here
runs fast because it is working on
C.
Here its library is written in C++, so
what do we do
here, we use it the most.
Now let's talk about which
required libraries will be needed for this, when
we work on it, first of all we will
need Python here because we are going to
work on Open Source Python,
by the way, you have Open Source here, you can work on Windows, that
means you can work on Android,
here you can also work on Mac OS,
and if we talk about it, then
see, I had told you in the beginning
itself that this C++
plus Python Java Mat Lab works on the
system here, so you can work with all these,
but our video is going to be
made, the video that
you are going to see in the coming future, what is all that  If it is
on the basis of Python, then basically Python should be
your first priority. I think
you should know the basic concepts.
After that, you should know the basic concepts. So,
number Python and
number Lipp and if we talk about these three,
what is special about these three? The playlist has been launched. So,
go there and first of all, you can learn the
free required libraries of these. For example, if you
have Python, then
first learn core Python.
After that, learn number five. Here,
after the egg, you will
need a sign file
because we are going to do scientific calculations here, so
now it will be needed.
And next, you will need a matrix here.
Matrix means matrix
calculations. You will
need the part related to mathematics.
You will need a vector
here because
we do calculations here with the help of all these things. Now see why you will
need a matrix
because whenever I do any image
thing, like I am doing an image,
if I am dividing this image into pixels,  I am
converting, I am
taking one of the pixels and
if I look at that pixel, then the
image that we get to see here, that image is
seen inside a matrix calculation,
so there we
should know matrix calculations,
how does the matrix calculation work, along with this, vector
calculations should also come, how does the vector work, how is it
performed,
all these things should be performed here, so
basically talking, you have this pre quad
here from the library, which is
very important for you to know, now if we talk about the model in Open Seaberry, then
inside Open, there are all these
code models, here we work
on the modules, further inside the video,
we will discuss about all these models van by van, what does the
code model do,
what does the image first model do, what is the model,
what is the video model, these are all the
models, that means you have small models inside it as well,
here which are your
different times,
we are going to see all these things in detail,
now I will
tell you all here that the modules of Open and
How can you install it in your system
so that you can download it? So
look, first of all, if you want to
open and download here, then I
will require you here that you have to install Jupyter Notebook
in your system.
We are going to download here through Jupyter Notebook.
Second thing is that after Jupyter Notebook,
you have to open and download it. So
what should you do first? Install Jupyter Notebook
in your system here. To
install the notebook, I will
give you a suggestion. If you go to a Chrome
browser,
after going to Chrome browser, you have to write
Anaconda here. Yes, what should you do here?
Write Anaconda. Yes, I should write here
Anaconda. You have to write download.
After downloading Anaconda,
you will reach the Anaconda
distribution. After downloading Anaconda, download Anaconda.
After downloading Anaconda,
its installation process is simple.
Download that installation process so
that the Anaconda system can be installed in your
Anaconda distribution.  It
can be downloaded inside your system and
inside it you get Jupyter notebook, the
second thing is how to get the model from open
here, so what you have to do is
come back to your Google, after coming to Google video,
write open and python here,
yes, open it, the
official website is
pypi.org, inside this you will find open and python,
click on it, here you will
see install open and pythagora,
just copy it,
after copying come down, after coming down
click on the command prompt here or you
can open the command prompt by writing CMD,
but let me tell you again,
come down here, after coming down here
you have to write CMD, by writing CMD,
your command prompt will open and here this
code is this pen stall open when python,
write it here, as soon as you enter,
this module from open will be
installed inside your system, so
at present it is inside our system, so
retirement is already showing satisfied
here, now this from open  How
can you reduce on the model, for this you will need
a piping file, so I will
open the Jupyter notebook in front of you all, on
which I am going to reduce all this, so
K UPA and Jupiter,
here I have
opened the notebook, on which I am reducing, if
you download it from Anaconda, then
inside Anaconda, your Jupyter notebook will automatically
open here, after that
what to do next here, if you do not have it in your system, then
it will
ask for installation,
what do you do here, write import,
after writing import, you have to write the
module of open, its name is cv2,
as if you run cv2, it will be
in your system and
you will not see any error here, so
what can you do in this way, you
can install cv2 in your system and you can
reduce your work on all the videos and
inside CBT you have
all the latest works from image processing and video processing,
today image and 3D image in it
You can easily work on all types of images here, so that's all for
today's
video. See you
with our next video, until then stay
with us and say goodbye
[praise] [music]
[music]